the answer is no psych therapy can be
helpful and it can help person deal with
particular issues for what he cannot do
is help the person understand the nature
of being reliable to having issues in
the first place
that's what only Dahmer can do that's
why it said the Dhamma is beyond mere
reasoning beyond mere cyclization
but it's not it doesn't mean the damage
is mystical or it pertains to some sort
of experience higher realms or something
no it just means that you understand the
nature of the thought the nature of
feelings the nature of intentions the
nature of perception and in order to be
able to understand it you have to start
stepping back from the pool of the
content of your feelings of your
intentions so that's
most simply described they were defined
and they would highlight the difference
between practice Adamo and pretty much
any other practice and in this case
attracted suicide there you don't want
to be concerned with overcoming the
content you want to be concerned with
understanding the nature of the content
in your liability to it so in that sense
and that's why dama dama is a universal
principle Universal being general being
meaning in common so what's in common to
any perception that you can have no
matter how different painful feelings
Pleasant feelings what's in common is
that they're feelings what's in common
is that they're perceptions so you see
and that's what the Buddha did also
describe the five aggregates he said any
form past the future present far or near
dear or or not they're personally
personal he knows form is there and then
he goes sent for any feeling and he
perception and intention any
consciousness so it doesn't matter the
content doesn't matter the significance
what matters is the presence hope that
of the nature of that country
and that's how you truly overcome being
affected by the content so psychotherapy
and all the other methods can enlighten
people in regard to the content and help
them under the relative basis but what
they cannot do is enable one to
understand the nature because you can't
at the same time before was Eddie
continent and then the nature of that
content so if you're concerned with a
particular type of feeling you're having
you're trying to get rid of it trying to
understand it trying to explain it you
cannot at the same time because by
transcending that content or that
feeling and seeing the nature of it in
the background she will either be
looking at the foreground or the beggar
you can't have it both so that's that's
what we cannot bring the insanity Lama
and the more you engage with it if you
do it on the account of thinking about
see now it means you're drifting away
from the Dharma further and further
because it's completely the opposite
direction it's looking at the general as
opposed to being concerned with a
particular so in that sense it cannot serve as a
so in that sense it cannot serve as a
replacement and also you can see that
the problem is not being affected by
this particular issue that particular
issue the problem is the true problem
the fundamental problem is being liable
to being affected by any issue
whatsoever so you might overcome many
issues but the fact is you don't
overcome you've been subject to further issues in
you've been subject to further issues in
the future that's where the bully would
say he recognized his subject so that's
why if one practice is the Dumber
psyctherapy as in management in regard
to the content dealing with the content
becomes redundant because you have a
proved a fundamental issue of being
liable to these things
thus no amount of particular
disagreeable manifestations of those
things can affect you so by being by
practicing the Dharma you make any other
method redundant and conversely it's not
true obviously by by still engaging in
various methods of management that there
indicates that the Dhamma is as in reach
fulfillment and if you develop a view on
account of those various methods being
valid practices of Dharma means you
won't be then finding while the real
track Sudama is as in the one that's
that metric opposed to that direction of
engaging with the particular content and
issues they might
so it's it's understanding the nature of
liability to suffering as opposed to
trying to deal with the particular
sufferings that and that thing come
through like taking up the
responsibility and then seeing the
difference in the opposite direction two
approaches one okay I lied and managed
with this particular thing that bothers
me
oh I'll step back and start reflecting
on the nature of being bothered in the
first place
and that's basically the beginning of
that little deflection they can leave to
the right practice
so if a person is able to distinguish
these two things and can't help
initially by using various methods like
therapist on to help themselves manage
with things that's absolutely fine but
it's not fine - mistake
and as I said I mean yeah the management
is fine but if if a person focuses on
the actual Dumber and it starts putting
in practice any such getting the results
normal management will be necessary
completely redundant because if a person
approved create a version delusion out
of their mind nothing they do isn't also
nothing that nothing can affect them in
their enforce manner so there is nothing
for them to manage hence they're free
from burden be from burden of action
free from having to do something in
order to be free because they're now
quick